Jonathan Chavarria

Full Stack Software & Mobile Engineer

⊚ jhon.chavarria@gmail.com

ghttps://github.com/jhon-chavarria

SUMMARY

Passionate Software Engineer with 15+ years of experience in developing web applications and backend systems. Skilled at writing clear, concise code that is easy to maintain and troubleshoot. Experienced in working with both small and large teams across multiple projects and companies. Able to work independently of remote locations.

Site: https://jhon-chavarria.github.io/

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Software Engineer & Mobile Engineer

2010 - Present

Freelance

- Freelance Software Engineer working with many different projects locally and external, Projects
 From USA, Canada, Mexico, Central America and South America.
- Main technologies Stack is: PHP (Laravel, Cake, Symfony), Android (Java, Kotlin), React (Next Js), Angular, VueJs, NodeJs (TotalJs, Express).

Full Stack Software Engineer

2020 - Present

RCN Capital | Direct Financing for Real Estate Investments

Connecticut, USA

- In charge of maintenance and adding new features of both, Backend and Frontend projects
- Designed, developed and maintained a robust loan origination system for Real Estate Investors, utilizing PHP, Cake PHP, Mysql, AWS, Jquery, Azure, Docker to support complex lending workflows.
- Integrated Rest Apis to streamline data exchange with third-party services.
- Successfully converted whole project from PHP Cake2 to PHP Cake3.

Full Stack Software Engineer

2020 - 2024

BairesDev

California, USA

- Participated on many different projects with variety of technologies,
 Clients From USA, Canada, Central America and South America, some of them as Team Lead,
 Technologies used like: PHP Laravel, Angular, Elasticsearch, Firebase, GitHub, AWS, Mysql
- Promoted to Internal team as BairesDev full time employee on 2022
- Be part of the website team project working in all the features related to this key component
 In the company, main objectives are to implement and maintain the new features of the website
 And promote good practices.
- Be Part the team who helped to migrate all BairesDev websites from Laravel PHP and Wordpress To use NextJs, NodeJs, Laravel PHP, AWS, GraphQL, Strapi. Docker, Laravel Livewire.

Full Stack Software Engineer & Mobile Engineer

2020 - 2020

Jumpers

Managua, Nic

- In charge of developing and maintenance Mobile platform Android Application for food delivery, developing both applications client application and Driver application.
- Main Developer in charge of developing and maintenance order portal to track and process order status received from Android Application
- Main Technologies stack: Android (MVVM Architecture) Laravel PHP, Symfony PHP and VueJs (Portal order Management)

Full Stack Software Engineer

2019 - 2020

Grupo Link

Quito, Ecuador

- In charge of developing and maintenance different website projects from different clients on Ecuador Claro, Movistar.
- in charge to maintenance server configurations using Linux to host all website applications and databases
- Main Technologies Stacks: PHP Laravel, Vuejs, React, Angular, Gitlab, NodeJs, Linux, MySql, MongoDB.



MOST PROUD OF

Loyalty

Good Ready to support the organization during the most difficult situations.

Courage

Good To take projects and tasks almost out of control and put them on track again.

Trust

Good To get respect from others through truth and honesty.

STRENGHTS

Soft Skills

Good Communication, adaptability, teamwork, problem-solving, time management and emotional intelligence.

Technical Skills

Years of experience working with many different technologies and clients around the world, USA, Europe, Central America and South America

Programming Languages & Frameworks

PHP (Laravel, Symfony, CakePHP), Android (Java, Kotlin), Javascript (React, Angular VueJs, NodeJs), CSS (Boostrap, Tailwind)

Database Managament

Mysql, PostgreSql, MongoDB, FireStore, AWS

Other Tools

ElasticSearch, Kibana, Git, Firebase, Docker, WordPress, SQL, Azure, PHP Storm, VsCode, Cursor, Google Cloud, DB2, SVN, Jekyll, Jquery,HTML, CSS, Tailwind, Drupal, Linux, Windows, Django, AS400, Javascript, Strapi, Laravel Livewire

Languages

Spanish

English



Full Stack Software Engineer & Mobile Engineer

2018 - 2019

Ser Licorera Nicaragua

Managua, NIC

Responsible for web and mobile development projects, Leading Android development
application for sales, various products like food, beverages, etc, the mobile application is
integrated with ERP (BPCS) to handle invoices, accounts receivable, accounts payable,
inventory, everything synchronized with ERP, main technologies used: Android (Kotlin), .Net
core for API, DB2

Full Stack Software Engineer & Mobile Engineer

2016 - 2018

Casa Pellas

Managua, NIC

Responsible for web and mobile development projects, Leading Android development
application for sales, the main products were all related to vehicles parts, the mobile
application is integrated with ERP (AS400) to handle invoices, accounts receivable, accounts
payable, inventory, everything synchronized with ERP, main technologies used: Android (Java),
JAVA EJB restfull and Angular

Full Stack Software Engineer & Mobile Engineer

2013 - 2016

Rain - NicaSource

Managua, NIC

- Responsible working on variety applications, website applications and mobile with clients from
- Main Technologies used: Android (Java), CakePHP, Drupal, Jekyll, Git, Html, CSS, Jquery, Javascript

Senior Software Engineer

2012 - 2013

Nuevo Diario Nicaragua

Managua, NIC

- Responsible for working on newsletter local website, in charge of developing and maintenance
 everything about the web application which provides news about Nicaragua, application visited
 by thousands of people locally in Nicaragua and outside Nicaragua, focus on performance and
 good quality code.
- Main Technologies used: PHP, Smarty Template Engine for caching, PostgreSql, Html, Css, Jquery, Javascript

Junior Software Engineer

2010 - 2012

Guegue Comunicaciones

Managua, NIC

Responsible working on variety applications with local companies at Nicaragua, website
applications using technologies like: PHP, Html, CSS, Jquery, Mysql, Server Administration

EDUCATION

System Engineering.

2005 - 2010

Universidad Centro Americana (UCA)

Managua, Nic